Shobhit Singh

Technology Analyst

Shobhit Singh

Tuinweg 101, Hoofddorp 2132 DN

+31615859068

Shobhit5@hotmail.com

Software developer with more than 6 years of professional experience as an Full Stack Engineer in development, maintenance and support of Authentication and Authorization solutions using Java and JavaScript. For me, Simplicity is the key to brilliance.

Tech Stack

JAVA Spring, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Tomcat, Weblogic

AWS EC2, RDS, VPC, CloudFormation, ECS, lambda, API gateway, S3, Route53

OIDC, OAuth 2.0, SAML 2.0, JWT, LDAP, XML, JSON

Tools & systems: IBM security Verify Access, Maven, GIT, Splunk, dynatrace, CloudWatch, postman, jmeter, Jenkins, JIRA, BCMS, Linux

Also Familiar with: TypeScript, PYTHON, Selenium

Experience

Liberty Global / Technical Analyst

via: Infosys Ltd

June 2019 - PRESENT, Amsterdam, Netherlands

Develop NodeJS and Spring based REST APIs to implement authentication and authorization capabilities. Deployment of those services using jenkins.

Design and Development of dashboards tools for TagValidation, AdMonitoring tool to inspect the health of test-cases and generating reports.

Static website hosting on S3/Heroku using AWS amplify and Route 53 and CloudFront.

Develop solutions for providing authorization and SSO to third party applications using OAuth, OIDC and SAML and additional authentication capabilities using OTP, QR Code, FIDO 2.0

Create web sequence diagrams and low level design based on High level solutions and requirements.

Migrated applications from on-prem to AWS and integration with AWS services like EC2 instances, RDS, lambda, IAM, X-ray and cloudformation templates.

Implemented solutions for maintaining and verifying the identities of the users and providing appropriate access.

Improved efficiency by automating various daily tasks using selenium.

Documentation and development of Unit Test Cases to validate the functionality of the code.

Incident management, defect triages, troubleshooting logs and resolving workflow errors in the production environment.

Supporting application Go-Live activities and debug issues on the go.

Proximus Global / Software Engineer

via: Infosys Ltd

Aug 2015 - June 2019, Bangalore India

Design and development Dashboard UI for the dashboard with React JS and automated health check.

Created a backend application for Adingestion to the Video using NodeJS (Express and chai framework) and MariaDB.

Employee login/provisioning web app using angularJS and Okta as ϵ provider.

Knowledge transfer session for parties located at multiple geolocation.

Created a chat project with Oracle DB

Education

Galgotias University /Bachelor of Technology

Jul 2011 - Jul 2015, Greater Noida

I learned the basics of programming and Electronics.

Graduated with 7.8 CGPA in Electronics and Communication Engineering.

Successfully Coordinated meeting for stammerers for straight one year.

Volunteer Experience

TISA

- Coordinated weekly SHG meetings for more than a year.
- Organized National level conference with other volunteers..
- Organized communication workshops in multiple cities.
- Led a team of volunteers for multiple events and provided guidance to new members.
- Conducted interviews to spread awareness stammering.
- Got featured in the company portal for leaders in change programs and events.
- Provide online support to the association to write content, create forms etc.

WWF

• Participate in events to spread awareness about animal welfare and city cleaning.